<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power Of Yet</title>
    <description>Empower young girls to embrace a growth mindset
 
 
</description>
    <link>https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 13:32:26 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 13:32:26 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Winner</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;and-the-winner-is-the-survey-results-are-finally-in&quot;&gt;And The Winner is… The survey results are finally in&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had four illustrators to choose from. It was relatively easy to reduce that number to two. But then it got really hard. Both illustrators are true artist and been very attentive to details. Friends and family gave mixed feedback, so I needed to collect more serious data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/powerofyet-blog/images/comparison.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;which-one-would-you-have-chosen&quot;&gt;Which one would you have chosen?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting is that the difference between all respondents compared to the group that at least has bought 1 children’s picture book in the last 5 years is not significant different at all. Both illustrations are perceived similar professional made, which is great. But in all other areas the data shows a clear winner!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the winner is….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/powerofyet-blog/images/page1a.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a look at the breakdown of the individual questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/powerofyet-blog/images/survey.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curious why people picked illustration A? Here is what people said why they love illustration A:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Great bright, gender neural colors- positive and sunny&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Great setting and perspective of Enna (close-up)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Facial expression very thoughtful, it perfectly conveys Enna’s annoyance about sleep time&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s so lovely how the activities ant thoughts of her day are illustrated and seem to come from her imagination&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Illustration leaves room for imagination – thoughts are open not limited&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Has a whimsical nature&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Very creative and artistic&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Enna looks like the girls next door, girls can identify with&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bright and vibrant&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so excited to work with this artist. I will keep you updated once the first pages will come in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 01:21:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/which-illustration/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/which-illustration/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Carol Dweck</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;carol-dweck-mindset--the-new-psychology-of-success&quot;&gt;Carol Dweck ‘Mindset – the new psychology of success’&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch that video to get a better understanding of what a growth mindset is and how it can benefit you and your child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;text-align:center;&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QGvR_0mNpWM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 01:21:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/carol-video/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/carol-video/</guid>
        
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to praise right</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;“Many of the things we do to motivate our kids are sapping their desire to learn”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once thought telling children how smart they are would give them confidence in their abilities, the desire to learn, and the hardiness to withstand difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“The self-esteem movement got it wrong. Praising children’s intelligence may boost their confidence for a brief moment, but by fostering the fixed view of intelligence, it makes them afraid of challenges, it makes them lose confidence when tasks become hard, and it leads to plummeting performance in the face of difficulty”&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research shows that praising the process—children’s effort or strategies—creates eagerness for challenges, persistence in the face of difficulty, and enhanced performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;“What we’ve found in study after study is that ability-praise backfires. Emphasising effort gives a child a variable that they can control. They come to see themselves as in control of their success. Emphasising natural intelligence takes it out of the child’s control, and it provides no good recipe for responding to a failure.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 01:21:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/how-to-praise/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/how-to-praise/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Growth Video</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-is-a-great-resource-to-explain-help-you-kid-to-understand-the-concept-of-a-growth-mindset&quot;&gt;This is a great resource to explain help you kid to understand the concept of a growth mindset.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This super cute video was developed in collaboration with Stanford University’s. The brain is a muscle, and like any other muscle it can grow and become better, if you train it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2zrtHt3bBmQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Apr 2017 01:21:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/growth-video/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/growth-video/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Recognize Mindsets</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;recognize-fixed-mindset-thoughts-and-replace-them&quot;&gt;Recognize Fixed Mindset Thoughts and Replace them&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kids learn a lot from observing and listening to you. So its crucial to recognize fixed mindset thoughts and then replace then in your every day life with growth mindset thoughts. In the beginning this will feel maybe a little weird but over time it will come naturally. Find below a a list with things to say instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/powerofyet-blog/images/sayings.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as a baby isn’t born talking but learns over time, they don’t know everything but can learn over time with work. A growth mindset helps children to believe that they can learn, change, and develop needed skills. They are better equipped to handle inevitable setbacks, and know that hard work can help them accomplish their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/powerofyet-blog/images/comic1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 01:21:47 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/recorgnize-mindset/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://esthercordova.github.io/powerofyet-blog/recorgnize-mindset/</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
